Charles B. Davenport Papers ca.1903-1940 Mss.B.D27
American Philosophical Society
- Series I. Charles B. Davenport Papers, 1878-1944; 43 linear feet (Box 1-97)
  - Bonin, Gerhardt von, 1890-?, 1930 Nov. 24 - 1931 Oct. 19; 5 items (Box 5)
  - Bonnevie, Kristine, 1907 May 7 - 1932 Feb. 13; 15 items (Box 5)
  - Bonney, A. F., 1911 Sept. 11 - Oct. 24; 2 items (Box 5)
  - Bordage, Edmond, 1897 Dec. 2 - 1899 Jan. 17; 3 items (Box 5)
  - Bordner, John S., 1904 Oct. 20 - Dec. 5; 4 items (Box 5)
  - Borodin, D. N. (Dmitrii Nikolaevich), 1921 Nov. 19 - 1923 May 22; 10 items (Box 5)
  - Borodin, N. A. (Nikolai Andreevich), 1861-1937., 1920 Aug. 3 - 1924 Aug. 6; 4 items (Box 5)
  - Bosanquet, Mrs. Charles (Schieffelin, Barbara), 1929-1932; 5 folders (130 items) (Box 5)
    Eugenics Record Office -- Psychology
    - Folder 1, 1929 Jan. 15 - Apr. 18; 25 items (Box 5)
    - Folder 2, 1929 Apr. 20 - Dec. 28; 28 items (Box 5)
    - Folder 3, 1930 Jan. 8 - 1932 Aug. 8; 33 items (Box 5)
    - Folder 4, 1929 Feb. 28 - Apr. 15; 22 items (Box 5)
    - Folder 5, 1929 Apr. 16 - July 12; 22 items (Box 5)
  - Boston Society of Natural History, 1898 May 6; 3 items (Box 5)
  - Bottigheimer, Mrs. Edgar M., 1932 Sept. 7-19; 2 items (Box 5)
  - Bouges, Louise, 1923 June 8-20; 2 items (Box 5)
  - Boulton, Laura C., 1933 July 8 - Oct. 14; 3 items (Box 5)
  - Boveri, Theodor, 1862-1915, 1910 Dec. 20 - 1926 Nov. 10; 4 items (Box 5)
  - Bovie, W. T., 1918 Jan. 29 - 1921 Nov. 25; 14 items (Box 5)
  - Bowditch, Cornelia, 1922 Apr. 7-15; 4 items (Box 5)
  - Bowditch, Harold, 1883-?, 1918 May 20 - 1923 Jan. 26; 26 items (Box 5)
  - Bowditch, Henry I., 1909 Sept. 10 - Oct. 26; 8 items (Box 5)
  - Bowman, Isaiah, 1918 Mar. 9 - 1929 Mar. 14; 15 items (Box 5)
  - Boyer, Claude E., 1932 Sept. 19 - Oct. 16; 3 items (Box 5)
  - Brace, Edith M., 1905 May 9; 1 item (Box 5)
  - Bradley, Helen A., 1923 Mar. 19; 1 item (Box 5)
  - Braem, F., 1891 Feb. 8 - 1904 May 25; 6 items (Box 5)
  - Brainerd, Ezra, 1908 Aug. 7-16; 2 items (Box 5)
  - Bralliar, Floyd, 1932 Jan. 24 - July 22; 2 items (Box 5)
  - Brand, Erwin, 1930 May 3 - Oct. 10; 6 items (Box 5)
  - Brandeis, Julian W., 1875-?, 1920 Nov. 26 - 1927 Apr. 29; 22 items (Box 5)
  - Brandt, Karl, 1902 May 23; 1 item (Box 5)
  - Breasted, James Henry, 1865-1935, 1919 May 16-27; 3 items (Box 6)
  - Breinl, Friedrich, 1888-1936, 1925 May 5 - 1926 Jan. 12; 17 items (Box 6)
  - Brewster, Edwin Tenney, 1866-?, 1895 July 29 - 1914 July 4; 12 items (Box 6)
  - Bridges, Calvin B. (Calvin Blackman), 1889-1938, 1916 June 12 - 1929 Dec. 17; 3 items (Box 6)
  - Briggs, Ella Marion, 1905 Jan. 16; 1 item (Box 6)
  - Briggs, L. B. R., 1897 Dec. 13 - 1899 Oct. 10; 3 items (Box 6)
  - Brigham, Carl Campbell, 1890-?, 1922 Dec. 21 - 1930 Mar. 17; 34 items (Box 6)
  - Bristol, Charles Lawrence, 1912 Sept. 5 - 1921 May 26; 7 items (Box 6)
  - Bristol, George P., 1906 Dec. 17-31; 2 items (Box 6)
  - Bristol, Lucius Moody, 1913 Nov. 1 - 1915 Nov. 2; 4 items (Box 6)
  - Britton, Elizabeth G. (Mrs. Nathaniel Lord), 1923 Jan. 3 - 1925 May 5; 16 items (Box 6)
  - Britton, Nathaniel Lord, 1859-1934, 1904 Apr. 20 - 1914 May 4; 16 items (Box 6)
  - Brockman, K. G., 1926 Oct. 19 - 1927 Mar. 16; 5 items (Box 6)
  - Bronfenbrenner, A., 1925 Feb. 14 - 1931 May 13; 31 items (Box 6)
  - Brooke, Charles Edward, 1904 Jan. 11; 1 item (Box 6)
  - Brooklyn Collegiate and Polytechnic Institute (Box 6)
    - Grades of C. B. Davenport, 1883 Feb. - 1884 Dec.; 11 items (Box 6)
    - Mechanical drawings of C. B. Davenport, n.d.; 1 notebook (Box 6)
    - Miscellaneous notes, 1874 Dec. 5 - 1940 June 1; 2 items (Box 6)
    - Statistics for the class of '85, 1885; 31 items (Box 6)
  - Brooks, Mrs. Charles F., 1928 Mar. 4-6; 2 items (Box 6)
  - Brower, Elbert O., 1928 Nov. 24 - Dec. 3; 2 items (Box 6)
  - Brown, C. J. D., 1932 July 20-28; 2 items (Box 6)
  - Brown, Constance, 1933 Mar. 18-26; 5 items (Box 6)
  - Brown, E. T., 1908 July 24 - 1909 Apr. 22; 4 items (Box 6)
  - Brown, Edward, 1907 Jan. 30 - 1911 Sept. 11; 30 items (Box 6)
  - Brown, Elmer Ellsworth, 1861-1934, 1911 Feb. 24 - Oct. 10; 6 items (Box 6)
  - Brown, Frank A., 1944 Feb. 19; 1 item (Box 6)
  - Brown, Herbert A., 1914 Mar. 21 - 1915 Oct. 14; 3 items (Box 6)
  - Brown, J. Stanley (Box 6)
  - Brown, Sanger, 1884-?, 1921 Feb. 8 - 1930 Mar. 12; 11 items (Box 6)
  - Brown, W. H., 1926 Aug. 24; 1 item (Box 6)
  - Brown, William Moseley, 1894-?, 1930 Apr. 23 - July 10; 12 items (Box 6)
  - Brownne, J. S., 1910 Dec. 30 - 1925 Jan. 29; 36 items (Box 6)
  - Brozek, Artur, 1912 May 1 - 1925 Mar. 23; 13 items (Box 6)
  - Bruce, B. K., 1907 Feb. 24; 1 item (Box 6)
  - Brues, Charles T. (Charles Thomas), 1879-1955, 1902 Apr. 2 - 1927 Apr. 4; 11 items (Box 6)
  - Brunetti, E., 1905 Oct. 20; 1 item (Box 6)
  - Brushfield, Thomas, 2 folders (Box 6)
    - Folder 1, 1925 Dec. 15 - 1928 Mar. 21; 21 items (Box 6)
    - Folder 2, 1928 May 31 - 1931 Jan. 15; 23 items (Box 6)
  - Bryan, William Alanson, 1908 Aug. 24 - Sept. 22; 3 items (Box 6)
  - Bryant, Louise Stevens, 1928 Oct. 1 - 1931 Dec. 21; 6 items (Box 6)
  - Bryce, George, 1844-1931, 1903 Sept. 29; 1 item (Box 6)
  - Bryn, Halfdon, 1922 Oct. 26 - 1929 Sept. 8; 2 items (Box 6)
  - Bryngelson, Bryng, 1933 Apr. 12; 1 item (Box 6)
  - Brynk, S., 1920 June 29 - July 5; 2 items (Box 6)
  - Buchinger, Ing. A., 1929 Mar. 14 - Apr. 17; 3 items (Box 6)
  - Buckhout, W. A., 1906 Nov. 22-26; 2 items (Box 6)
  - Bullard, Charles, 1898 Aug. 27 - 1900 Mar. 15; 6 items (Box 6)
  - Bulletin of Social Hygiene, Editor, 1919 Sept. 8; 1 item (Box 6)
  - Bullington, Walter Edward, 1890-?, 1925 Aug. 28 - 1933 Nov. 27; 14 items (Box 6)
  - Bumpus, Hermon Carey, 1862-1943, 1891-1915; 2 folders (54 items) (Box 6)
    Cold Spring Harbor Laboratory; Conferences and symposia; International Congress of Zoology; National Academy of Sciences; Political issues; Scientific organizations, meetings, programs
    - Folder 1, 1891 Mar. 25 - 1907 Nov. 15; 21 items (Box 6)
    - Folder 2, 1908 Jan. 28 - 1915 May 19; 33 items (Box 6)
  - Bumstead, Henry Andrews, 1870-1920, 1920 Jan. 31 - Sept. 15; 11 items (Box 6)
  - Bunch, Cordia C., 1885-?, 1933 Nov. 22-27; 2 items (Box 6)
  - Bunting, Martha, 1899 Feb. 27 - 1900 Feb. 8; 3 items (Box 6)
  - Buol, Mary Stilwell, 1932 Aug. 31 - Oct. 25; 2 items (Box 6)
  - Burbank, Luther, 1849-1926, 1907 May 13 - 1921 Jan. 13; 8 items (Box 6)
  - Burdeen, C. R., 1905 Jan. 30 - Feb. 4; 2 items (Box 6)
  - Burgess, G. K. (Georoge Kimball), 1874-?, 1929 Apr. 30 - May 20; 4 items (Box 6)
  - Burke, John J., 1925 Nov. 20 - 1930 Aug. 28; 13 items (Box 6)
  - Burlingame, Leonas Lancelot, 1876-?, 1922 Mar. 15 - Dec. 5; 8 items (Box 6)
  - Burnham, Allen M., 1932 Mar. 4 - 1933 June 22; 4 items (Box 6)
  - Burr, Allston, 1943 Aug. 4; 1 item (Box 6)
  - Burr, Carll S., Jr., 1858-?, 1907 Apr. 16 - 1908 Apr. 27; 9 items (Box 6)
  - Burt, Edward A., 1897 June 21 - 1899 Mar. 22; 2 items (Box 6)
  - Burt, Luella, 1931 Jan. 30 - Aug. 15; 15 items (Box 6)
  - Butler, Nicholas Murray, 1862-1947, 1910 May 25 - 1924 Feb. 4; 9 items (Box 7)
  - Buxton, Leonard Halford Dudley, 1930 Mar. 29 - Apr. 21; 3 items (Box 7)
  - Byrnes, Esther Fussell, 1866-?, 1916-1940; 3 folders (83 items) (Box 7)
    Biographical and personal data; Cold Spring Harbor Laboratory; Conferences and symposia; Eugenics Record Office
    - Folder 1, 1916 Jan. 30 - 1920 June 16; 25 items (Box 7)
    - Folder 2, 1920 June 17 - 1927 Jan. 26; 30 items (Box 7)
    - Folder 3, 1926 Feb. 1 - 1940 Mar. 5; 28 items (Box 7)
  - Cadwalader, John, 1932 Apr. 19-20; 3 items (Box 7)
  - Calder, William M., 1869-?, 1919 Sept. 8 - 1922 Feb. 23; 7 items (Box 7)
  - Caldwell, Otis W. (Otis William), 1869-1947, 1925 Oct. 6 - 1930 Sept. 15; 33 items (Box 7)
  - Calkins, Gary Nathan, 1867-1943, 1901 Dec. 11 - 1930 Feb. 11; 10 items (Box 7)
  - Calvet, Louis, 1868-?, 1898 Oct. 23 - 1904 Oct. 14; 4 items (Box 7)
  - Camp, Mrs. Blanche M. (Letchworth Village), 1926 June 26 - 1932 Nov. 29; 30 items (Box 7)
  - Campbell, C. G. (Clarence Gorden), 1868-1956, 1927-1932; 2 folders (53 items) (Box 7)
    Eugenics; Eugenics Research Association; Research support
    - Folder 1, 1927 Mar. 21 - 1928 July 6; 20 items (Box 7)
    - Folder 2, 1928 July 9 - 1932 Aug. 9; 33 items (Box 7)
  - Candelas, P. B., 1942 July 4-17; 7 items (Box 7)
  - Cannon, Gertrude L., 1910 Jan. 9 - Oct. 12; 14 items (Box 7)
  - Cannon, H. Graham, 1923 Nov. 19 - 1925 June 19; 3 items (Box 7)
  - Cannon, Walter B.(Walter Bradford), 1871-1945, 1896-1934; 2 folders (45 items) (Box 7)
    Bibliographical matters; Biographical and personal data; National Academy of Sciences; National Research Council; Research support
    - Folder 1, 1896 Aug. 1 - 1925 Jan. 14; 23 items (Box 7)
    - Folder 2, 1925 Mar. 24 - 1934 Jan. 29; 22 items (Box 7)
  - Cannon, William Austin, 1870-?, 1903 Nov. 5 - 1903 Nov. 21; 4 items (Box 7)
  - Carlson, Anton J. (Anton Julius), 1875-1956, 1904 Apr. 10 - Nov. 7; 3 items (Box 7)
  - Carlson, Elof Axel, 1971 Jan. 26; 1 item (Box 7)
  - Carlson, H. C., 1932 Nov. 18-29; 4 items (Box 7)
  - Carnegie, Mrs. Andrew (Louise W.), 1925 Dec. 16; 1 item (Box 7)
  - Carnegie Endowment for International Peace, 1933 Feb. 21-23; 2 items (Box 7)
  - Carnegie Institution of Washington (Box 7-9)
    See also Series II.
    Business; Carnegie Institution of Washington; Cold Spring Harbor Laboratory; Committee activities -- Executive committee; Conferences and symposia; Genetics; Publication; Research support
    - Folder 1, 1929 Jan. 5 - Feb. 27; 31 items (Box 7)
    - Folder 2, 1929 Mar. 1-28; 29 items (Box 7)
    - Folder 3, 1929 Apr. 1 - June 30; 32 items (Box 7)
    - Folder 4, 1929 Jul. 5 - Dec. 1; 20 items (Box 7)
    - Folder 5, 1930 Jan. 7 - Dec. 12; 31 items (Box 7)
    - Folder 6, 1931 Jan. 9 - Dec. 22; 36 items (Box 7)
    - Folder 7, 1932 Jan. 4 - June 27; 34 items (Box 7)
    - Folder 8, 1932 July 8 - Dec. 31; 31 items (Box 7)
    - Department of Genetics (Box 7-8)
      - Folder 1, 1913 Jan. 20 - 1921 May 6; 40 items (Box 7)
      - Folder 2, 1921 Nov. 29 - 1923 Oct. 8; 45 items (Box 7)
      - Folder 3, 1923 Oct. 10 - 1925 July 22; 52 items (Box 7)
      - Folder 4, 1925 Sept. 10 - 1928; 51 items (Box 7)
      - Folder 5, 1927 Dec. 14 - 1928 June 23; 36 items (Box 7)
      - Folder 6, 1931 Feb. 13 - 1933 Mar. 17; 26 items (Box 8)
      - Budget, 1924 Jan. 24 - 1933 Oct. 19; 35 items (Box 8)
      - General, 1929 - 1932 June 20; 37 items (Box 8)
      - Program, 1923 Dec. 2 - 1939 Feb. 8; 11 items (Box 8)
      - Report of staff meeting, 1935 Jan. 21 - 1937 June 7; 34 items (Box 8)
      - Staff meetings, 1922 Jan. 5 - 1928 Oct. 1; 22 items (Box 8)
    - Executive Committee: Minutes of the Meetings, 1929 Jan. 11 - 1930 Jan. 17; 7 items (Box 8)
    - Gilbert, William Marshall, 1879-?, 1927-1939; 32 folders (Box 8-9)
      Biographical and personal data; Carnegie Institution of Washington; Cold Spring Harbor Laboratory; Committee activities; Conferences and symposia; Eugenics; Genetics; Human evolution, physical anthropology; Human genetics; International Congress of Genetics -- Fifth Congress; National Research Council; Political issues; Publication; Referee's report; Research support; Travel -- Invitations, arrangements
      - Folder 1, 1927 Jan. 5 - Feb. 26; 32 items (Box 8)
      - Folder 2, 1927 Mar. 1 - Apr. 29; 29 items (Box 8)
      - Folder 3, 1927 May 2 - July 22; 32 items (Box 8)
      - Folder 4, 1927 Aug. 2 - Sept. 27; 28 items (Box 8)
      - Folder 5, 1927 Oct. 3 - Nov. 30; 44 items (Box 8)
      - Folder 6, 1927 Dec. 2 - 1928 Feb. 28; 36 items (Box 8)
      - Folder 7, 1928 Mar. 1-19; 40 items (Box 8)
      - Folder 8, 1928 Mar. 20 - Apr. 23; 46 items (Box 8)
      - Folder 9, 1928 May 7 - Dec. 26; 62 items (Box 8)
      - Folder 10, 1929 Jan. 9 - Apr. 26; 36 items (Box 8)
      - Folder 11, 1929 May 4 - Aug. 30; 41 items (Box 8)
      - Folder 12, 1929 Sept. 3 - Dec. 30; 42 items (Box 8)
      - Folder 13, 1930 Jan. 2 - Mar. 31; 55 items (Box 8)
      - Folder 14, 1930 Apr. 1 - June 12; 49 items (Box 8)
      - Folder 15, 1930 June 14 - Oct. 13; 46 items (Box 8)
      - Folder 16, 1930 Oct. 14 - Dec. 31; 54 items (Box 9)
      - Folder 17, 1931 Jan. 3 - May 28; 60 items (Box 9)
      - Folder 18, 1931 June 1 - Aug. 27; 58 items (Box 9)
      - Folder 19, 1931 Sept. 1 - Oct. 16; 48 items (Box 9)
      - Folder 20, 1931 Nov. 31 - Dec. 31; 38 items (Box 9)
      - Folder 21, 1932 Jan. 4 - Apr. 6; 50 items (Box 9)
      - Folder 22, 1932 Apr. 7 - July 21; 62 items (Box 9)
      - Folder 23, 1932 July 21 - Dec. 29; 64 items (Box 9)
      - Folder 24, 1933 Jan. 4 - Feb. 25; 34 items (Box 9)
      - Folder 25, 1933 Feb. 27 - Apr. 20; 58 items (Box 9)
      - Folder 26, 1933 Apr. 19 - Sept. 5; 55 items (Box 9)
      - Folder 27, 1933 Sept. 6 - Dec. 28; 63 items (Box 9)
      - Folder 28, 1934 Jan. 3 - Apr. 30; 56 items (Box 9)
      - Folder 29, 1934 May 1 - June 29; 52 items (Box 9)
      - Folder 30, 1934 July 1 - Sept. 15; 49 items (Box 9)
      - Folder 31, 1934 Sept. 18 - Dec. 28; 69 items (Box 9)
      - Folder 32, 1936 Nov. 24 - 1939 Nov. 30; 4 items (Box 9)
  - Carpenter, Thorne Martin, 1878-?, 1926 July 20 - 1929 May 28; 12 items (Box 10)
  - Carrel, Alexis, 1873-1944, 1912 Oct. 17 - 1933 Nov. 24; 6 items (Box 10)
  - Carrier, Lillian S., 1933 Mar. 20; 1 item (Box 10)
  - Carrington, E. S., 1907 Aug. 31 - 1921 Apr. 28; 22 items (Box 10)
  - Carrington, Hereward, 1880-1959, 1932 June 23 - Oct. 19; 4 items (Box 10)
  - Carris, Lewis Herbert, 1869-?, 1924 Nov. 10 - 1931 Mar. 25; 11 items (Box 10)
  - Carruth, William Herbert, 1859-1924, 1913 Apr. 15 - 1916 May 19; 8 items (Box 10)
  - Carty, John Joseph, 1861-1932, 1919 Nov. 18 - 1925 Dec. 23; 10 items (Box 10)
  - Case, Clarence Marsh, 1874-1946, 1921 Mar. 28 - Apr. 9; 4 items (Box 10)
  - Casteel, Dana B., 1905 June 17 - 1906 Mar. 2; 4 items (Box 10)
  - Castle, William E. (William Ernest), 1867-1962, 1893-1940; 13 folders (323 items) (Box 10)
    Biographical and personal data; Carnegie Institution of Washington; Cold Spring Harbor Laboratory; Eugenics; Genetics; Human genetics; Mouse genetics; Poultry genetics; Rat genetics; Recommendations; Requests for aid in finding positions; Scientific organizations, meetings, programs; Travel -- Invitations, arrangements
    - Folder 1, 1893 - 1904 Sept. 18; 29 items (Box 10)
    - Folder 2, 1904 Oct. 8 - 1906 Aug. 24; 29 items (Box 10)
    - Folder 3, 1906 Oct. 2 - Dec. 28; 25 items (Box 10)
    - Folder 4, 1907 - 1908 Feb. 12; 27 items (Box 10)
    - Folder 5, 1908 May 13 - Dec. 21; 23 items (Box 10)
    - Folder 6, 1909; 24 items (Box 10)
    - Folder 7, 1910; 41 items (Box 10)
    - Folder 8, 1911-1912; 25 items (Box 10)
    - Folder 9, 1913; 16 items (Box 10)
    - Folder 10, 1914 Mar. 6 - 1915 Apr. 22; 20 items (Box 10)
    - Folder 11, 1916 Jan. 4 - 1919 Sept. 23; 18 items (Box 10)
    - Folder 12, 1921 Nov. 2 - 1924 Oct. 20; 25 items (Box 10)
    - Folder 13, 1925 Feb. 5 - ca. 1940; 21 items (Box 10)
  - Cattell, James McKeen, 1860-1944, 1898-1931; 10 folders (366 items) (Box 10)
    Academic freedom; Anthropology; Bibliographical matters; Committee activities; Conferences and symposia; Human evolution, physical anthropology; National Academy of Sciences; Publication; Recommendations; Scientific organizations, meetings, programs
    - Folder 1, 1898 Feb. 18 - 1903 July 3; 28 items (Box 10)
    - Folder 2, 1904 Jan. 16 - 1908 Aug. 26; 36 items (Box 10)
    - Folder 3, 1908 Oct. 10 -1 909 Apr. 17; 36 items (Box 10)
    - Folder 4, 1909 May 17 - 1913 Mar. 2; 40 items (Box 10)
    - Folder 5, 1913 Apr. 2 - 1915 Sept. 30; 40 items (Box 10)
    - Folder 6, 1915 Oct. 1 - 1917 Nov. 16; 40 items (Box 10)
    - Folder 7, 1917 Nov. 11 - 1921 Apr. 29; 40 items (Box 10)
    - Folder 8, 1921 July 20 - 1924 June 19; 40 items (Box 10)
    - Folder 9, 1924 Oct. 1 - 1926 Nov. 29; 30 items (Box 10)
    - Folder 10, 1928 Jun. 1 - 1931 Aug. 22; 36 items (Box 10)
  - Cattell, Owen, 1930 Nov. 22-25; 3 items (Box 10)
  - Caullery, Maurice, 1868-1958, 1902 May 28 - 1933 Apr. 5; 11 items (Box 10)
  - Cavallucci, Nicholas, 1921 Oct. 5 - Nov. 13; 4 items (Box 10)
  - Cesa, F., Apr. 18-25; 2 items (Box 11)
  - Chadwick, H. C., 1902 Nov. 28 - 1903 May 27; 3 items (Box 11)
  - Chamberlain, T. C., 1908 May 28 - 1921 Jan. 7; 11 items (Box 11)
  - Chaney, L. Beverley, 1933 Sept. 26; 1 item (Box 11)
  - Chaplin, W. S., 1887 Sept. 15; 1 item (Box 11)
  - Chapman, Frank M. (Frank Michler), 1864-1945, 1908 Apr. 30 - May 6; 3 items (Box 11)
  - Chapman, R. H., 1908 Dec. 23 - 1909 Jan. 15; 3 items (Box 11)
  - Chapman, Royal N., 1933 Mar. 14; 1 item (Box 11)
  - Charlton, O. C., 1904 Feb. 22; 1 item (Box 11)
  - Chase, Ernest L., 1940 Sept. 23; 1 item (Box 11)
  - Chase, Stuart, 1931 Dec. 29-30; 2 items (Box 11)
  - Chen, Shisan C., 1923 Dec. 13; 1 item (Box 11)
  - Cheney, Ralph H., 1933 June 23-29; 2 items (Box 11)
  - Cherrie, George Kruck, 1865-?, 1900 Sept. 5 - 1901 Dec. 20; 16 items (Box 11)
  - Chester, W. M., 1905 May 10; 1 item (Box 11)
  - Child, Charles Manning, 1869-1954, 1904 Sept. 1 - 1905 July 26; 6 items (Box 11)
  - Chilton, Charles, 1919 June 14 - 1926 Aug. 28; 11 items (Box 11)
  - Chinn, Aubyn, 1933 Feb. 11 - Mar. 3; 3 items (Box 11)
  - Chittenden, R. H., 1907 Feb. 25 - 1931 Nov. 3; 11 items (Box 11)
  - Christian, Henry A., 1918 Apr. 10 - 1921 Dec. 21; 21 items (Box 11)
  - Chrystal, Charlotte L., 1917 Feb. 19 - Mar. 5; 3 items (Box 11)
  - Claghorn, Kate Holladay, 1916 Feb. 8; 1 item (Box 11)
  - Clark, Austin H., 1901 Jan. 20 - 1902 Jan. 10; 4 items (Box 11)
  - Clark, Helen, 1926 June 8-9; 2 items (Box 11)
  - Clark, Hubert Lyman, 1900 Jan. 7 - 1901 Oct. 28; 6 items (Box 11)
  - Clark, John Bates, 1847-1938, 1918 Jan. 4-7; 2 items (Box 11)
  - Clark, L. Pierce, 1921 Jan. 5 - 1932 Nov. 21; 42 items (Box 11)
  - Clark, Marian K., 1914 Nov. 21 - 1916 May 18; 22 items (Box 11)
  - Clark, Mary Aug., 1921 Apr. 12 - 1923 Nov. 15; 5 items (Box 11)
  - Clarke, John Mason, 1857-1925, 1908 Dec. 2 - 1923 Apr. 3; 25 items (Box 11)
  - Clarke, S. F., 1899 Feb. 17 - 1925 Aug. 13; 6 items (Box 11)
  - Clausen, J., 1933 July 17; 1 item (Box 11)
  - Clements, Frederic E. (Frederic Edward), 1874-1945, 1922 Nov. 20-29; 4 items (Box 11)
  - Clinton, L. A., 1910 Mar. 9 - May 4; 11 items (Box 11)
  - Clymer, Mrs. May, 1933 June 7-26; 2 items (Box 11)
  - Cockerell, Theodore D. A. (Theodore Dru Alison), 1866-1948., 1898 Oct. 23 - 1913 Dec. 22; 27 items (Box 11)
  - Cocks, William R., 1906 Mar. 24 - 1911 Feb. 14; 30 items (Box 11)
  - Coe, Wesley Roswell, 1869-?, 1898 Feb. 28 - 1904 May 9; 5 items (Box 11)
  - Cohen, Th E de Jonge (Box 11)
  - Colby, Frank Moore, 1865-1925, 1900-1902; 2 folders (68 items) (Box 11)
    Publication
    - Folder 1, 1900 July 13 - 1901 Aug. 29; 39 items (Box 11)
    - Folder 2, 1901 Sept. 18 - 1902 Aug. 13; 29 items (Box 11)
  - Cold Spring Harbor, 1902-1940; 9 folders (Box 11-12)
    Biographical and personal data; Business; Cold Spring Harbor Laboratory; Genetics; Research support
    - Beginnings - Correspondence, 1902-1904; 3 folders (49 items) (Box 11)
      Business; Carnegie Institution of Washington; Cold Spring Harbor Laboratory; History of biology, especially genetics; Shull, George Harrison
      - Folder 1, 1902 Jan. 22 - May 5; 15 items (Box 11)
      - Folder 2, 1903 May 3 - Dec. 29; 17 items (Box 11)
      - Folder 3, 1904 Jan. 2 - Apr. 27; 17 items (Box 11)
    - Home Defense Corps, 1917 Apr. 2 - 1920 Feb. 9; 8 items (Box 11)
    - Station for Experimental Evolution, 1911-1924; 3 folders (193 items) (Box 11)
      Business; Cold Spring Harbor Laboratory
      - Folder 1, 1911 Oct. 25 - 1919 July 18; 54 items (Box 11)
      - Folder 2, 1919 Aug. 17 - 1923 May 16; 65 items (Box 11)
      - Folder 3, 1923 June 20 - 1924 Dec. 27; 74 items (Box 11)
    - Village Improvement Society, 2 folders (Box 12)
      - Folder 1, 1909 May 28 - 1910 Oct. 12; 45 items (Box 12)
      - Folder 2, 1911 May 11 - 1940 Sept. 19; 51 items (Box 12)
  - Cole, Leon Jacob, 1877-?, 1906-1929; 2 folders (66 items) (Box 12)
    Committee activities; International Congress of Genetics -- Sixth Congress; Poultry genetics; Scientific organizations, meetings, programs; Travel -- Invitations, arrangements
    - Folder 1, 1906 Nov. 27 - 1914 Nov. 17; 34 items (Box 12)
    - Folder 2, 1915 Jan. 14 - 1929 Oct. 25; 32 items (Box 12)
  - Cole, William H., 1933 Nov. 17; 1 item (Box 12)
  - Colton, Harold Sellers, 1881-?, 1906 Nov. 15; 1 item (Box 12)
  - Columbia University, 1933 May 11 - July 17; 3 items (Box 12)
  - Committee For A State Police, 1914 Aug. 18 - 1917 May 26; 11 items (Box 12)
  - Committee of the National Research Council for Research on Sex Problems, 1924 Nov. 29 - 1925 Dec. 27; 9 items (Box 12)
  - Committee on the American Negro, 1926 Nov. 21 - 1931 Oct. 28; 20 items (Box 12)
  - Committee on Animal Development (J. C. Merriam), 1929 Dec. 30 - 1931 Apr. 9; 9 items (Box 12)
  - Committee on Bibliography of Science, 1910-1923; 3 folders (69 items) (Box 12)
    American Association for the Advancement of Science; Bibliographical matters; Committee activities; National Research Council; Publication
    - Folder 1, 1910 - 1920 Mar. 30; 31 items (Box 12)
    - Folder 2, 1920 Apr. 6 - May 28; 36 items (Box 12)
    - Folder 3, 1923 Mar. 31 - June 12; 2 items (Box 12)
  - Committee on Evolution Controversy, 1922 May 2 - 1925 May 10; 19 items (Box 12)
  - Committee on Heredity in Relation to Disease, 1924 Dec. 6 - 1927 Jan. 27; 11 items (Box 12)
  - Committee on Human Behavior, 1921 Oct. 20 - 1924 Oct. 16; 13 items (Box 12)
  - Committee on Radiation, 1929 Feb. 2 - 1930 Mar. 3; 4 items (Box 12)
  - Comstock, E. (transferred to new folder: "Twinkling Star") (Box 12)
  - Comstock, John Henry, 1849-1931, 1898 Oct. 15 - 1899 Nov. 13; 5 items (Box 12)
  - Concilium Bibliographicum, 1904-1932; 3 folders (97 items) (Box 12)
    Bibliographical matters; Committee activities; Publication; Travel -- Invitations, arrangements
    - Folder 1, 1904 Apr. 22 - 1913 Nov. 10; 62 items (Box 12)
    - Folder 2, 1923 Jan. 3 - 1925 Dec. 30; 20 items (Box 12)
    - Folder 3, 1926 Jan. 21 - 1932 Dec. 24; 15 items (Box 12)
  - Condolences for C. B. Davenport, 1944 Feb. 18-28; 78 items (Box 12)
  - Conference on Physical Basis of Human Behavior (Box 12)
  - Conferencia Panamericana, 2nd (Box 12)
  - Conklin, Edwin Grant, 1863-1952, 1896-1931; 6 folders (284 items) (Box 12-13)
    Academic freedom; Bermuda Biological Station; Eugenics; Evolution; Fellowships, assistantships; Genetics; Human genetics; Marine Biological Laboratory, Woods Hole; National Academy of Sciences; Political issues; Poultry genetics; Publication; Recommendations; Requests for aid in finding positions; Research support; Scientific organizations, meetings, programs; Solicitations for support or contribution; Travel -- Invitations, arrangements
    - Folder 1, 1896 Jan. 6 - 1912 Dec. 5; 46 items (Box 12)
    - Folder 2, 1913 Jan. 13 - 1919 Dec. 11; 43 items (Box 12)
    - Folder 3, 1920 Jan. 27 - 1924 Dec. 17; 52 items (Box 13)
    - Folder 4, 1925 Feb. 28 - 1929 Dec. 23; 54 items (Box 13)
    - Folder 5, 1930 Jan. 4 - Aug. 30; 38 items (Box 13)
    - Folder 6, 1930 Sept. 2 - 1931 Dec. 29; 51 items (Box 13)
  - Conn, Herbert William, 1895 Jan. 3 - 1916 Aug. 30; 10 items (Box 13)
  - Cook, Arthur E., 1923 June 28; 1 item (Box 13)
  - Cook, Robert Carter, 1898-?, 1922-1931; 2 folders (65 items) (Box 13)
    Eugenics; International Congress of Eugenics -- Third Congress; International Congress of Genetics -- Sixth Congress; Publication; Scientific organizations, meetings, programs
    - Folder 1, 1922 Aug. 29 - 1928 Oct. 1; 28 items (Box 13)
    - Folder 2, 1930 Mar. 15 - 1931 Dec. 9; 37 items (Box 13)
  - Cook, S. J., 1933 May 8-10; 2 items (Box 13)
  - Cooley, Grace E., 1904 May 24 - 1905 June 4; 3 items (Box 13)